The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
Even within that brilliant history,
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
にもかかわらず—
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
A phantom sixth man.
幻のシックスマンがいた と
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       ninjacloud
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（観客１）うおお ３本連続
That's three in a row!
（観客２）これが“キセキの世代”
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)か！
So this is Midorima Shintaro of the Generation of Miracles!
Captain.
（緑間）キャプテン
（大坪(おおつぼ)）あ？
What?
You're finished?
（大坪）もういいのか？
（緑間）はい
Yes, I have a feel for it.
感触は確かめられました
Shutoku............................................................Ginbo
They're taking him out after only five minutes?
（黄瀬(きせ)）５分もしないでもう温存
あっちのほうは余裕みたいっスね
Those guys seem to be taking it easy.
Of course they are.
（笠松(かさまつ)）ま 当然だ
相手もフツーの中堅校だし—
Their opponent is just a middle-tier school.
There should be no surprises.
波乱はまずねーだろ
If there are going to be any, it'll be over here.
あるとすりゃあ
こっちなんだが…
Seirin
Episode 9
To Win
（岩村(いわむら)）うん
（黒子(くろこ)）うっ？
Their passing is ridiculous!
（火神(かがみ)）このパス回し—
They're so quick to immediately pass the ball right after they get it!
もらってから投げるまでが
メチャクチャ速(はえ)え！
Mitobe, he's gone!
（日向(ひゅうが)）水戸部(みとべ) 行ったぞ！
（ホイッスル）
（審判）ファウル！ 白10番！
Foul! White 10!
Hey, isn't that his third one already?
（日向）オイオイ
てかもう３つ目じゃね？
Damn it!
（火神）くそ 動きが速い
They're not only fast.
They don't waste any movements.
つーよりモーションが少ない
It's like they're passing the ball without ever catching it.
構えねーで投げてる感じだ
Is this another one of their martial arts techniques?
これも古武術かよ
火神っちの得点で誠凛(せいりん)もエンジン
かかったと思ったんスけど—
I thought Seirin's engine was finally running when Kagamicchi scored,
but they haven't managed to take another step.
あと一歩うまくいかないっスねー
You can't call yourself a king just for playing good defense.
ディフェンスだけじゃ
王者は名乗れねーよ
Their offense is exceptional too.
オフェンスだって並じゃねえ
ふーん
Seiho may not have prodigal scorers like you or Kagami,
確かに正邦(せいほう)に
オマエや火神みてーな—
天才型のスコアラーはいねーけどな
but they're a different type of team.
タイプが違うんだよ オフェンスも
古武術を応用してる
They incorporate old martial arts into their offense too.
Seiho isn't a team of prodigies.
正邦は天才のいるチームじゃねえ
達人のいるチームなんだよ
They're a team of experts.
There are some experts
（黄瀬）達人ならいるっスよ
（笠松）うん？
on Seirin too.
（黄瀬）誠凛にも
（ホイッスル）
（審判）アウト･オブ･バウンズ！
Out of bounds! White ball!
白ボール！
Seirin.....................................Seiho
A nine point difference, huh?
（津川）９点差か〜
Seirin.....................................Seiho
Sorry.
（黒子）すみません
（津川）君は…
You!
Who are you? Have you been playing this game?
誰！？ てか出てたっけ試合？
I'm Kuroko Tetsuya. I have been.
黒子テツヤです 出てました
You're kidding! Seriously?!
（津川）うっそだー マジ！？
存在感なさすぎっしょー
You've got so little presence!
（火神）過去対戦済みなのに
忘れられてる！
He's played him before, but doesn't remember him!
（日向）しかも
フツーに名乗っとる！
And he just normally told him his name!
You're a first year too?
オレと同じ１年？
Hey, did you know?
ねえ知ってる？
去年 ウチの先輩たち—
Last year, our team was ahead of yours by 20 points in the first quarter.
君んとこに第１クオーターで
20点差つけたらしいんだ
（日向）くっ…
（津川）だからオレ—
That's why I want to make it 30.
30点差ぐらいつけたくてさー
Well, don't let it get you down!
ま ガッカリしないでね！
（黒子）分かりました
（津川）ん？
Fine.
（黒子）
ガッカリしないように頑張ります
I will make sure I am not disappointed.
They've been right on them all game.
（降旗(ふりはた)）
マジずっとベッタリじゃん
They can barely pass like that.
（河原(かわはら)）パス回すのもしんどいよ
（伊月(いづき)）ふっ…
A random pass like that will never...
（春日(かすが)）
苦し紛れのパスが通るわけ…
（岩村）なに！？
ディフェンスの裏からパスが…
What? A pass from behind the defense?
What was that pass?
（観客１）何だ 今のパス！？
ブーメランみたいに戻ってきた
It came back like a boomerang.
No, it didn't.
（観客２）戻ってねーよ 誰かが
タップして向き変えたんだよ！
It came back because someone tapped it.
（観客１）誰かって誰？
（観客２）さあ？
Someone? Who?
Who knows?
フフッ…
鉄壁の正邦ディフェンスも—
Looks like the iron wall of Seiho's defense
has never seen a pass from inside their wall before.
壁の内側からパスくらったことは
ないみたいっスね
（大室(おおむろ)）くそっ…
（坂本(さかもと)）どーなってんだ
Damn it.
What the hell's going on?
Now, now.
まあまあ落ち着きんしゃい〜
Calm down, kids.
Crap!
（伊月）しまった…
He doesn't seem strong, but he's fast!
（伊月）
すげえ力感(りきかん)ねえのに 速い！
っしょ〜い
There!
あらら
What?
Seirin's waking up!
（観客１）誠凛
がぜん勢いづいてきた
Seirin...................................................Seiho
（歓声）
（観客）おお スリー！
A three!
First quarter over!
（審判）第１クオーター終了
そういえば さっき
またこいつがバカ言ったそうだな
I heard this guy said something stupid again.
Yeah.
あー ぶっちゃけ
去年のトラウマ思い出したし
Honestly, it brought back memories of last year's trauma.
すまんな
Sorry.
けどまあ… 全然いいっスよ
But it's totally cool.
Seirin..........................................Seiho
We got over it.
乗り越えたし
We're tied.
（津川）同点…
ビミョー つか ありえねえ
Weird! I mean, this is impossible!
We're not anywhere close to our goal!
全然目標達成できてなくね？
Tsugawa!
（岩村）津川！
（津川）えっ
Don't get ahead of yourself. Shut your trap.
調子に乗るな 黙れ
ううっ うぐっ…
If any of you have the same ideas as Tsugawa, remember this...
もしこの中に今の津川と
同じようなことを—
少しでも思ってるヤツがいたら
改めて肝に銘じろ
They're strong.
あいつらは強い
格下などと間違っても思うな
Make sure you don't think they're weaker than us!
Yeah, yeah. Don't underestimate them.
（松元(まつもと)）うんうん
油断は禁物だ
岩村はちゃんと分かってるね
Iwamura, you understand.
お互い高校生だ
勝負が終わるまで—
We're both high school teams.
No one knows what will happen until it's over.
何が起こるか分からん
毛ほどもスキを作るな
Don't leave any gaps.
This game is...
まだ勝負は…
...just getting started!
（リコ）始まったばかりよ！
Keep the same formation!
フォーメーションはこのままでいく
ただパス回しにつられすぎてるから
ゾーンは少しタイトに
You're being lead around by their passes too much,
so tighten your zone.
あと火神 ファウル多い
Also, Kagami,
you have a lot of fouls.
If you just try to timidly match your opponents,
相手に合わせようなんて
腰が引けちゃ流れ持ってかれる
they'll control the flow of the game.
Remember to attack!
（リコ）攻める気持ちが大事よ
（選手たち）おう！
Yeah!
The second quarter will now begin!
（オフィシャル）
第２クオーター始めます
もうさっきみたいに
抜かせないからね！
You won't get past me again.
They're playing even tighter defense.
一段と厳しくなりやがった
Tokyo's best defense is finally running at full power.
（小金井(こがねい)）いよいよ東京最強の
ディフェンス全開か
（火神）くっ この野郎…
Seriously, this guy...
I can't get past him.
マジでこいつ… 抜けねえ！
But,
けど…
２人だったら！
with the two of us...
What was that?
（津川）今 何を？
（火神）うっ
（岩村）させん
No, you don't!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
What was that?
（観客１）何だ 今のは？
（観客２）２人抜きだったぜ
They blew past two guys!
They can do that ?
あんな連係プレーもあんのかよ！
Where did No. 11 come from just now?
てか11番 今どっから出てきた！？
あのディフェンスをぶち破るかよ
They can break through that defense?
They're more in tune with each other than they were before.
前より２人の息が
合ってるっスね
But there's one thing bothering me.
（笠松）けど… １つ気になるな
第２クオーターで
かく汗の量じゃねーぞ あれは
That's way too much sweat for the second quarter.
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（火神）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
What are you smiling about?
（春日）
なーに抜かれて笑ってんの？
あっ すいません
Oh, sorry!
I mean, it's fine.
いーけどさー 別に
火神のオーバーペースだろ？
うれしいのは
You're happy Kagami's over exerting himself, aren't you?
Looks like your plan's working well.
いい感じにオマエのマークが
効いてんじゃん
Not yet! He needs to suffer more!
まだまだ！
もっと苦しんでくんないと！
おお〜 なんと頼もしいドＳっぷり
You're quite the sadist.
That pair's offensive power is certainly impressive,
それに あの２人
攻撃力は確かにスゲーけど—
but only one of them can score.
点取れるのは１人だけでしょ？
ハァ ハァ…
（火神）ん？ 何だ 急に…
What's going on?
They're not pressuring me at all.
全然プレッシャーかけてこねえ
They're not trying to stop me?
止める気もねーのか？
I don't know what they're thinking,
何考えてよーが知るか！
上からぶちこんでやる！
but I'll slam another one down!
No! Don't do it, Kagami!
（日向）ダメだ 行くな火神！
（津川）うっ
（審判）オフェンスファウル！
白10番！
Offensive foul!
White 10!
（観客１）４つ…
うわぁ ４つ目だー
That's four.
That's his fourth!
Seirin's scorer is in foul trouble!
（観客２）誠凛のスコアラーが
ファウルトラブル！
He did that on purpose!
（火神）こいつ… わざと…
That idiot! What is he doing?
バッカ！ 何やってんスか もー
こりゃ
引っ込めるしかねーな
He'll have to back down.
残り１つじゃ ビビって
まともにプレーはできねー
With only one foul left, he can't play as aggressively as usual.
まだ第２クオーターっスよ
It's only the second quarter!
That moron!
（小金井）バッカたれ！
Excuse me. I'd like to make a substitution.
（リコ）すみません
交代お願いします
大丈夫すよ こんくらい！
もうファウルしなきゃいいんだろ？
I'll be fine!
I just have to make sure I don't get any more fouls, right?
I can do it!
いけます！
Well, this works out perfectly.
ま ちょうどいいわ
We were planning on subbing you and Kuroko out anyway.
オマエと黒子は どーせ
引っ込めるつもりだったからな
（火神）え？
（黒子）ボクもですか？
Me too?
We decided before the game started that you'd only play the first half.
最初から決めてたからな
オマエら２人は前半までだって
そんな なんでだよ… ですか！
But why? Why would you do that?
（日向）理由は１つ
For one reason.
緑間を倒すには
オマエら２人が必要だからだ
In order to beat Midorima,
we need you two.
Even if we win this game,
もしこの試合に勝ったとして—
次の秀徳(しゅうとく)に勝つには
緑間攻略が必須条件だ
we need a strategy to beat Midorima and Shutoku for our next game.
As we predicted,
けど予想通り 秀徳は
既に緑間を温存している
Shutoku is already conserving Midorima's strength.
We can't win if you two are spent.
消耗したオマエらじゃ勝てない
But if we lose this game, we won't even have the chance—
だからってこの試合に負けたら
元も子も…
We know it's a gamble.
（日向）
バクチだってのは分かってるさ
But if we can conserve the two of you,
けど オマエら２人を
温存できれば—
秀徳を倒し 決勝リーグへ行ける
可能性がわずかに残るんだ
we'll have a slim chance of beating Shutoku and reaching the championship league.
We'll beat Midorima even if we're tired, so let us—
いや 疲れてても何とかして
緑間を倒してみせますよ！
（火神）だから…
（黒子）火神君
Kagami, let's do as they say.
言う通りにしましょう
What?
I believe in our seniors.
ボクは先輩たちを信じます
（日向）まあ心配すんな
Well, don't worry.
We'll beat Seiho.
正邦は… オレたちが倒す
（ホイッスル）
（オフィシャル）誠凛—
Seirin, member change.
メンバーチェンジです！
I haven't played in forever.
（土田(つちだ)）
いやー ひっさしぶりだわ 出んの
Let's show them what we can do, Tsucchi.
んじゃ いいとこ見せちゃおーぜ！
ツッチー
If things start to go badly, I'll play!
ヤバくなったら出ます！
What are you talking about? You've got four fouls.
（小金井）４ファウルが
何言ってんだ！ 任しとけ！
Leave this to us.
Two?
２人？
They subbed out their two first years.
１年両方 引っ込めてきたか
Oh? They're both gone.
あーらら！ ２人とも
いなくなっちゃったかー
It's a little disappointing, but whatever!
まぁちょっと物足りないけど…
いっか！
Quit running your mouth, you braggart.
（日向）
ガタガタうるせぇぞ 茶坊主が
チャ チャボウ…
B-Braggart?
I'm going to teach you how to properly talk to your seniors, baldy.
今からオマエに先輩への口のきき方
教えてやる ハゲ
（秀徳部員たち）行け 行け 秀徳
Go, go, Shutoku!
Hey, hey.
Seirin benched their first years.
誠凛１年コンビ
引っ込めちまったぞ
Are they throwing the game?
勝負投げたのか？
No, they're doing just the opposite.
（緑間）いや… むしろ逆だ
（岩村）ぐっ
（日向）だあっ…
They intend to win.
（緑間）あの目は… 勝つ気だ
Seirin...................................................Seiho
He can dunk?
ダンクできたんかい
Nice dunk, Mitobe.
（日向）ナイスダンク 水戸部
Hey.
（岩村）おい
I heard your conversation.
さっきの話聞こえたが
まさか秀徳に勝つつもりとは—
You think you can beat Shutoku?
You're underestimating us.
ウチもナメられたものだな
Oh, that was just talk.
（日向）あんなん建前っすよ
（岩村）建前？
Talk?
これはオレたちにとっての雪辱戦
This is our revenge game.
We can't brag about it if we win on the backs of our first years.
後輩たちの力借りて勝ったところで
威張れないじゃないですか
とどのつまり 先輩の意地だよ
Ultimately...
This is just the seniors' will.
Seniors? You're just a year older than me.
先輩っても
オレと１つ違うだけじゃん ハハハ
（津川）うっ
（大室）オマエもうマジ黙っとけ！
Seriously, shut up!
I accept your challenge.
受けて立とう 来い！
Bring it on!
We won't hold back.
（日向）んじゃ 遠慮なく
行くぞ 正邦！
Let's go, Seiho!
Stoic Resolve
Seiho High School Basketball Club
（歓声）
（リコ）行け行け！ そこ〜！
何を深刻な顔してんの！
Why do you look so serious?
They're not that bad, so don't worry.
みんな そんなヤワじゃないから
大丈夫よ！
Yes!
ウス！
（大室）ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（大室）もらった！
（日向）さすかっ！
Got it!
No, you don't!
（河原）おお スゲェ！
（福田(ふくだ)）止めたぁ！
Amazing!
He blocked it!
This form...
（岩村）このフォームは…
Could he have
こいつ まさか
フックシューターか！
a hook shot?
This didn't happen last year.
（岩村）去年はなかった…
He's learned a new trick.
小癪な技を覚えたな
Looks like you haven't been playing around this past year.
（岩村）１年間
遊んでたわけではなさそうだな
No problem. This is nothing!
なんの〜 まだまだ
Oh, no you don't!
（伊月）くっ させるか！
ん？ この距離から
レイアップだと？
He's trying to lay it up from this far out?
A scoop shot?
スクープシュートか！
こんな柔らかいタッチ
見たことねえ
I've never seen such a soft touch.
If Iwamura's a rigid player, that guy's flexible.
岩村が剛(ごう)の選手なら
あいつは柔(じゅう)って感じだ
Go, go, Seirin!
行け行け 誠凛 押せ押せ 誠凛
Do it, do it, Seirin!
Here!
（小金井）
はい！ はあ はあ…
おお〜っ 思ったより
全然くらいついてるっスね
They're going at it harder than I expected.
This seems to be working a lot better.
てかむしろ
今のほうがしっくりきてるけどな
They formed a team around Kuroko and Kagami this spring.
黒子と火神を加えたチーム編成は
春から作った型—
In other words, it's still developing.
いわば発展途上だ
Hyuga's outside shots and Mitobe's hook shots.
日向のアウトサイドシュートと
水戸部のフックシュート
The offensive style revolving around those two that they're playing right now
それを軸にしてチームオフェンスで
点を取る今の型が—
is the other set up Seirin spent a year creating.
誠凛が１年かけて作った
もう１つの型だ
They must have been practicing hard to win since they lost last year.
あいつらは去年の敗戦から—
相当練習してきたんだろ
勝つために
One other thing I noticed is this team's
あと もう１つ分かったのは—
key player is the guy I matched up against the other day.
こっちのチームの
キーマンは—
オレがこの前
マッチアップしたあいつだ
うん？ キャプテンじゃないんスか
It's not their captain?
Hyuga is their mental core.
（笠松）日向は精神的支柱だ
ゲームメイクは
ポイントガードに任せる
He leaves the playmaking up to the point guard.
He most likely has another eye.
あいつはたぶん 眼がもう１つある
An eye?
（黄瀬）眼？
One! Let's be careful!
１本！ ここ大事に行くぞ！
あっ イッテー
Ow.
（観客１）おお 決まった！
（観客２）すげえよ 誠凛
He scored!
Seirin's amazing!
They're holding their own against King Seiho!
（観客３）王者正邦に負けてねえ
はあ はあ はあ… クッソ
右サイドで展開してたのに…
Damn it, I was on his right side...
...but he used me as a screen.
逆サイドのオレを
スクリーン代わりに使いやがった
（春日）マジかい？
Seriously?
今のタイミング 上から
全体見てるぐれーじゃねーと…
That happened so fast.
You'd never notice unless you were watching from above.
Izuki can see it.
（リコ）伊月君は見えるのよ
（火神）ん？
He's got an eagle eye.
イーグルアイを持ってるからね
An eagle eye?
イーグルアイ
He's not particularly athletic, but he can change his perspective on the play instantaneously inside his head.
彼は身体能力は
恵まれてないけど—
頭の中で視点を瞬時に変えられる
つまり ものをいろんな角度から
見れるから—
Because he sees the play from every angle,
he always sees the entire court.
常にコート全体が見えてるのよ
Seriously?
マジかよ
It'd be nice if you'd call that a nice shot.
今のシュート
ナイスじゃナイッスか？
Do you want to be subbed out already?
今すぐ交代するか 死ね
Go die.
Die?
（伊月）え 死…？ え！？
What?
Hyuga and the others aren't good at everything,
日向君たちは万能じゃないけど
みんな１つは特技を持ってる
but they each have one special skill.
They've been polishing them for a whole year.
しかもそれを１年間磨いてきたのよ
They really are amazing!
やっぱスゲェっス 先輩たち！
Do Koganei and Tsuchida have special skills too?
じゃあ小金井先輩と土田先輩も…？
Huh? Uh, yeah.
うりゃー
Koganei can shoot from anywhere!
（リコ）
小金井君はオールレンジから
シュートが打てるわ！
（１年生たち）おお〜
But his accuracy's only so-so!
（リコ）けど成功率はそこそこ
Doesn't that make him pretty normal?
それ 結構普通じゃね？
（小金井）だは〜
What are you doing?
何やってんだ〜
And Tsuchida is good at rebounding!
（リコ）そして土田君は
リバウンドが得意！
うっ 小金井！
Koganei!
I got it!
任しとけ
がはっ…
Enough already!
いい加減にせい！
How did you miss two open shots?
なんでフリーで２回も外してんだよ
Seirin...............................................................Seiho
（坂本）
チッ これはライン出るか
It's going out of bounds.
What?
（小金井）どお！
（リコ）小金井君 大丈夫？
Koganei, are you oka—
Or not!
（リコ）じゃない！
（福田）わあぁ 目回してる！
His eyes are spinning!
Koganei?! Koganei?!
小金井君！ 小金井君！？
（火神）先輩 大丈夫なんスか
Senpai, are you okay?
I think it's a light concussion.
軽い脳しんとうだと思うけど
交代しかないかも…
We might have to sub him out.
Then let me play!
じゃあオレを出してくれ
…ださい！
Please!
What are you talking about?!
（日向）何言ってんだ
オマエはダメだ
You can't play!
Have you forgotten why we're conserving your energy?
その元気は何のために
とってるか 忘れたんか
We'll settle this. You just wait!
ちゃんとケリつけてくっから
待っとけ！
だからってジッとしてらんねーよ！
But I can't just sit still!
オレだって先輩たちの力に…
I want to help—
ボクもそう思います
I agree,
so the guy with four fouls should stay on the bench.
だから４ファウルの人は
すっこんでください
（火神）ぐっ…
なんだと黒子 テメエ…
What'd you say, Kuroko?
出ても津川君にまたファウルしたら
即退場じゃないですか
If you foul Tsugawa again,
you'll just be thrown off the court.
I won't!
しねーよ！ だから—
I've got to pay Tsugawa back for what he did!
オレは津川にも借りがあんだよ！
Fine.
（黒子）分かりました
（火神）ん？
じゃあ津川君は
ボクが代わりに倒しときます
I will beat Tsugawa in your place.
What?
（火神）はあ！？ 何だよそれ？
What good will that do?
There's no point if you beat him!
オメエが倒したって意味ねえだろう
Seirin.............................................Seiho
What are you talking about?
Five more minutes, and it's a six point difference.
（日向）あと５分… ６点差か…
（火神）くう…
（日向）分かった
Fine. As another first year, take down Tsugawa, Kuroko.
じゃあ１年生同士
津川は頼むわ 黒子
What?
Seirin, member change.
（オフィシャル）誠凛
メンバーチェンジです
あっ なんだー 君だけ？
It's just you?
オレ 火神と
やりたかったんだけどなー
I wanted to play against Kagami.
Sorry, I may not be very strong,
（黒子）すみません
力不足かもしれませんが—
but he apparently has a grudge, so I'm here to pay it back.
借りがあるそうなんで
返しに来ました
By proxy.
代理で
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
（火神）オレがベンチなんて…
I can't believe I've been benched!
（リコ）信用しなさい！
Have some faith in the will of Kuroko and your seniors.
黒子君と
先輩の意地ってやつをね
We'll win this game against Seiho
決勝リーグ進出をかけて
この正邦戦 取るわよ！
and play the championship game!
（火神）これに勝てれば
秀徳との決戦… おう！
If we win this game, we'll play against Shutoku!
Episode 10
I Can't Have That